ALICE CHAN MEI YOKE

Home Address : 15, Jalan SS14/5H,

47500 Subang Jaya, Selangor Darul Ehsan.

Contact Number : 012-640 3133 Personal E-mail : a1yz@hotmail.com



MY PROFILE

IC No. : 740531-14-5326
Birth Date : 31st May 1974
Birth Place: Kuala Lumpur
Nationality : Malaysian
Race : Chinese
Gender : Female

Interest : Live Music, Movies, Food & Dining, Swimming and Networking.

About Me: I am a fast learner, pro-active, aggressive, dynamic, independent, responsible, focused and a hard working person (alone or as a team). Able to adapt and improvise to improve self or team efficiency. Enjoy working in a fast-paced environment. Meticulous, systematic, well organized with strong people and communication skills. Good at multi-tasking, problem solving and discipline with excellent attendance and punctuality at work.

• Job Specialization: Purchasing, Supply Chain, Shipping, Logistics & Customer Service.

LANGUAGES

- English (Spoken & written)
- Bahasa Malaysia (Spoken & written)
- Cantonese (Spoken only)
- Mandarin (Spoken only)

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Microsoft Office Word & Excel
- Online Research

PREFERENCES

Availability : 2 weeksWork Location : Selangor

• Requirement : 5 day work week

• Expected Salary: RM 4,000.00 – 4,500.00 per month

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATION

Diploma in Hotel Management – CGPA: 3.24

NPC Institute of Hotel Management, Petaling Jaya (May 1994 - May 1996)

• Certificate in Hotel Operations – CGPA: 2.9

NPC Institute of Hotel Management, Petaling Jaya (Jul 1992 – Jul 1993)

- Certificate of High Performance Mandarin Beginner Programme Distinction Ernesco Language Centre, Petaling Jaya (May 1997)
- Certificate of High Performance Japanese Beginner Programme Completed Ernesco Language Centre, Petaling Jaya (Jul 1996)
- Certificate in Public Relations Attended

Institute of Public Relations Malaysia, Stamford College, Petaling Jaya (Jun 1997 – Dec 1997)

Certificate in Teambuilding Programme

RSH Training Centre (M) Sdn. Bhd., Awana Resort, Genting Highlands (Jul 2000)

- Certificate of Vessel Familiarization from Tanjung Pelepas, Johor to Hong Kong On board mother vessel Karen Maersk voyage 0107 including one full watch on the bridge, in the engine room, during cargo operations & Hong Kong terminal introduction (Aug 2001)
- Certificate of Fundamentals of International Trade & Understanding Bills of Lading Tradelinks Resources Consultancy Sdn. Bhd., Petaling Jaya (Aug 2001)
- Certificate of Customer Service Training Program

Sales Development Programs Pte. Ltd., Singapore (Nov 2001)

Certificate in Maersk Sealand E-Driver's Licence 2002

Maersk Malaysia Sdn. Bhd., Petaling Jaya (Jun 2002)

Certificate of Making A Difference (MAD) – Self Development Course

Zubedy (M) Sdn. Bhd., Mont Kiara, Kuala Lumpur (Apr 2005)

Certificate of Microsoft Excel 2003 – Beginning

Nota Asia (M) Sdn. Bhd., Petaling Jaya (May 2005)

Certificate of Urban Pest Management

Malaysian CropLife and Public Health Association, Petaling Jaya (Nov 2007)

Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia (SPM)

Sekolah Menengah Sultan Salahuddin Abdul Aziz Shah, Shah Alam (Nov 1991)

• Sijil Rendah Pelajaran (SRP)

Sekolah Menengah Sultan Salahuddin Abdul Aziz Shah, Shah Alam (Nov 1989)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Position: Regulatory Affairs & Marketing Executive (Mar 2011 – Nov 2013)
 Company: Acucare Systems (M) Sdn. Bhd. (Healthcare & Medical Device Distributor)

Reporting to : Business Development Manager & Managing Director

Software : Microsoft Dynamics NAV Classic Monthly salary: RM 3,500.00 + 500.00 (Allowance)

Reason for leaving: Seeking better career advancement opportunities and exposure.

Job Responsibilities:

Head and coordinate the ISO 9001:2008 and GDPMD (Good Distribution Practice for Medical Device) activities. Ensure that a company's products comply with the regulations of the Malaysia Medical Device Bureau (MMDB). Update product pricing and create new item code and details. Email correspondence with the Principals on pricing matters. Obtain the Sales Funnel reports from the Sales team on a weekly basis. Prepare monthly Statistics report on the Sales Funnel after discussion with the Business Development Manager. Internal coordination for exhibition matters with the relevant departments. Internal coordination for tender projects matters with the relevant departments. Appointed to be a Personal Assistant to the Managing Director.

Position: Sales & Marketing Coordinator (May 2009 – Jul 2010)
 Company: Laboff (M) Sdn. Bhd. (Laboratory Fittings Manufacturer)

Reporting to : Managing Director

Software : Microsoft Office Excel & Word (Improvised)

Monthly salary: RM 2,700.00

Reason for leaving: Skin allergy to Polypropylene materials.

Job Responsibilities:

Head the Office Operations from after Sales to sourcing and negotiating material price with Suppliers, costing, purchasing, production, packing, delivery (for Export and local), documentations (filling, invoicing, purchase order, delivery order, shipping documents and etc.). Credit control and store (inventory and stock control). Prepare monthly Purchasing and Sales reports.

Position: Senior Operations Executive (Jun 2007 – Oct 2008)
 Company: Bumipest Sdn. Bhd. (Fumigation & Pest Control Specialist)

Reporting to : Chief Executive Officer

Software : Microsoft Office Excel & Word (Improvised)

Monthly salary: RM 3,000.00

Reason for leaving: Seeking better career advancement opportunities and exposure.

Job Responsibilities:

Head the Operations division on enquiries, daily job scheduling for 5 technical teams, documentations (including Penang branch), filling, contracts and assisting other departments such as Admin (claims, forms, letters), Accounts (invoicing and credit control) and Store (purchasing, inventory and stock control). Prepare monthly Sales report and was appointed by the CEO to be the company's Management Representative for ISO 9001:2000.

Position : Purchasing Executive (Jul 2005 – May 2007)

Company : Sillner Industries (M) Sdn. Bhd. (Semiconductor Machine Manufacturer)

Reporting to : Purchasing Manager & Executive Director

Software : SQL (Sequel Query Language)

Monthly salary: RM 2,500.00

Reason for leaving: Company relocated

Job Responsibilities:

Handle the local and overseas Suppliers on pricing for raw materials and spare parts. Sourcing and developing new Suppliers. Negotiate for the best price to ensure a profitable margin. Issue Purchase Orders and follow-up the outstanding orders to ensure timely delivery. Liaise with Shipping Agent on goods clearance and custom duty for Import shipments. Coordinate with Accounts on credit control. Inventory and stock control. Coordinate with production on assembly and manufacturing. Documentation, filling and prepare purchase price comparison and costing reports.

Position : Documentation Executive, Sea Export & PA to MD (Aug 2004 – Jul 2005)

Company : Hanjin Shipping Line Malaysia Sdn. Bhd. (MNC Shipping Line)

Reporting to : Documentation Manager & Managing Director, Documentation Centre

Software: N.I.S. (New Information System)

Monthly salary: RM 1,800.00 Reason for leaving: Better offer

Job Responsibilities:

Prepare Sea Way Bill (SWB) against shipper's Shipping Instructions (SI). Check and ensure all shipping details are accurate and correct before SWB submission. Appointed to be a temporary Personal Assistant to Managing Director and Human Resource Manager to assist them in all general administrative matters pertaining to the Documentation Centre.

• Position: Customer Service Executive, Sea Export (Jan 2000 – Jan 2003)

Company : Maersk Malaysia Sdn. Bhd. (MNC Shipping Line)

Reporting to : Customer Service Manager

Software : M.C.S. (Maersk Communication System)

Monthly salary: RM 1,800.00

Reason for leaving: Assisting a friend to set up a Café and a Cafeteria (1 year contract).

Job Responsibilities:

Handle shipper's bookings/confirmations for worldwide export cargo. Attend to shipper and consignee's inquiries, quotation, emails/telexes, sailing schedules, handle complaints and problem solving. Monitor weekly long-standing container listing. Corresponding with overseas office to check updated filing rates and shipment instructions. Send loading advice to overseas offices for them to monitor the status of import shipments especially for VVIP/A1/Global accounts.

Position : Customer Service Executive, Sea Export (Mar 1999 – Jan 2000)
 Company : Kuehne & Nagel (M) Sdn. Bhd. (Freight Forwarder & Logistics)

Reporting to : Sea Freight Manager

Software: AS400 Monthly salary: RM 1,500.00 Reason for leaving: Better offer

Job Responsibilities:

Handle shipper's bookings/confirmations for worldwide export cargo. Attend to shipper and consignee's inquiries, quotation, emails, liner's sailing schedules, handles complaints and solving problems. Corresponding with overseas office to check updated filing rates and shipment instructions. Check the shipper's credit limits and shipment terms. Prepare Shipping Instructions (SI) and send pre-advise to overseas offices to monitor the import cargo status. Prepare and confirm House Bill of Lading (HBL) against shipping line's Sea Way Bill (SWB). Sort all relevant shipping documents and send it to the shipper and overseas office for consignee to claim their cargo once cargo arrived. After shipment completed, close all files for storing in the warehouse.

REFERENCES

Mr. Ricky Khor

Pan Pacific Glenmarie Resort Shah Alam – Manager (Resigned)

Mobile: 012-686 2977 Office: 03-3392 6888

Miss Agnes Tan Laboff (M) Sdn. Bhd. – Director (Current)

Mobile: 016-228 2711

Office: 03-5621 0166 / 0169